<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Biospreadr</title><link>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Biospreadr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Suction Mechanism Updates and Progress on Mechanical Simulation</title><link>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-4/</guid><description>Week 6 Suction Mechanism: Updates Construction This past week was the Winter reading week, so we took advantage of the opportunity to make a lot of progress on the suction mechanism.
We were able to get the base construction complete including wiring for the controller, shield, vacuum pump, ultrasonic sensor, and power system. In addition to the base assembly, we integrated a push button to start the process of lifting the dish lid with the suction mechanism and an LED used for error signalling.</description></item><item><title>Starting on the Suction Mechanism and Carrier Tube progress</title><link>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-3/</guid><description>Week 5 Carrier Tube: Electrical Updates This week was a lot of troubleshooting for the work on the carrier tube mechanism. The datasheet for the solenoid indicated that it could operate when supplied 5-6V with 0.8-1A. After testing out various power supplies rated at 5V and 1-1.2A, the carrier tube was still not working as intended. As seen in the following video, the solenoid could only retract when assisted by an external force.</description></item><item><title>More progress on the Carrier Tube Mechanism</title><link>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-2/</guid><description>Week 4 Carrier Tube: Mechanical Updates After getting the initial prints completed last week, this week was spent refining the mechanics of the carrier tube system and testing everything prior to handoff for electrical/software integration. Initial test fits revealed that the solenoid cavity in the 3D printed part was too small to fit the solenoid. There was a similar problem last week with the inner carrier tube being too small which was solved by sanding down the part.</description></item><item><title>Kicking things off, ordering parts, and 3D printing</title><link>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://biospreadr.github.io/blog/post-1/</guid><description>Welcome! This is our first blog post out of many that will be coming over the next few months. We&amp;rsquo;ll be documenting our progress as we implement the designs we created last term for our automated sample preparation device, BioSpreadr. Included in the posts will be updates on the building, testing, and development of the project. We&amp;rsquo;ll document the major challenges we&amp;rsquo;re facing, significant breakthroughs that happen during development, and anything else that might be interesting!</description></item></channel></rss>